westminster.ac.uk 2012-05-01

# University of Westminster - About us - Privacy

The website www.westminster.ac.uk and its subdirectories and subdomains (the “website”) is provided and managed by the University of Westminster of 309 Regent Street, London W1B 2UW (the “University”).

## Our Privacy Statement

The University is committed to protecting the privacy and confidentiality of information provided by you and all users of the website.  Accordingly the University upholds the relevant data protection principles and processes your personal data in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. You should read this privacy policy carefully to understand how the University uses and protects the information that you provide to it.

By providing your information to the University, you consent to the collection, use and transfer of your information in accordance with this privacy policy. We may amend this privacy policy at any time and any amended version will apply as soon as it is posted on the website. Please check for updated versions regularly.

If you have any questions or comments about this privacy policy, please contact the University in writing addressed to The Registrar and Secretary, 309 Regent Street, London, W1B 2UW

## Collection of your information

When you visit, register on or request information through the website you may be asked to provide certain information about yourself including name and contact details and other personal information. The University may also collect information about you and your use of the website from emails or letters you send to the University, from web forms you complete on the website and by the use of cookies.

Providing any personal information to the University is strictly voluntary. However, we may not be able to provide you with certain information or services if you do not provide the information requested.

For children who visit the website, special rules apply. The University does not request personal information about children. Where it is clear that an email has been sent or a web form has been completed by a child, their email address and any other personal information is not used for any reason other than in response to their email or web form.

## Use of your information

We may contact you by email, post, telephone or fax as appropriate. Your information may be used to:

  * provide you with information and publications that you have requested and to respond to your comments and queries;
  * notify you about important changes or developments to courses or other University services or to the website;
  * provide you with a full range of alumni and external affairs activities, including but not limited to sending you University publications, the promotion of alumni benefits and services and notification of alumni and other events;
  * enable the University to provide you with access to secure areas of the website where appropriate;
  * contact you as part of a fund raising programme; and
  * provide you with further information about the University or to otherwise contact you where the University considers it necessary or appropriate.

If you no longer wish us to contact you for any of these reasons or at all, please let us know by contacting the Information Compliance department via email at: M.Maruma@westminster.ac.uk ,or in writing to Information, Compliance,  University of Westminster, Room UG01, 309 Regent Street, London, W1B 2UW.

You may also opt out of receiving certain communications at the point you provide your information through certain web forms on the website.

## Disclosure of your information

The information you provide to us may be accessed by or transferred to the University’s:

  * academic and administrative departments;
  * international offices and partnerships, some of which are located outside of the European Economic Area;
  * alumni associations and societies, and sports and other clubs associated with the University; and
  * agents contracted for specific alumni-related projects.

Unless required to do so by law, the University will not otherwise share, sell or distribute any of your personal information without your consent.

The University uses security measures to protect your information from access by unauthorised persons and against unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction and damage. The University will retain your information for a reasonable period or as long as the law requires.

Countries outside of the European Economic Area do not always have strong or any data protection laws. However, the University will always take steps to ensure that your information is used by third parties in accordance with this privacy policy.

## Links

The University is not responsible for the privacy and data protection practices of any websites to which links are included on the website. You should be aware when you leave the website and move to any linked or other website, and you should read the privacy and data protection policies and statements contained on any such website.

## 

Cookies are small amounts of information stored on your computer by your browser as a result of accessing the website. Using cookies enables the University to monitor website traffic and to personalise the content of the website to your requirements. This maximises the benefits you gain in using the website and makes it easier to log on and use the website during any future visits.  

The University may use cookies to collect information about your use of the website whether or not you are registered for any secure areas of the website. Cookies do not contain any information that personally identifies you. They record information such as the domain name from which you access the website and the date and time of your access.

You may view the website without the use of cookies by disabling cookies in your internet browser, but this may limit your access to the website or certain functionality without the website. If you use the website without disabling cookies, you consent to the University collecting and using information obtained from cookies.

## Access to and updating your information

You are entitled to see the information held about you and you may ask us to make any necessary changes to ensure that it is accurate and kept up to date. If you wish to do this, please contact the Information Compliance department by email at: [dpa@westminster.ac.uk](mailto:dpa@westminster.ac.uk) or in writing to University of Westminster, Room UG01, 309 Regent Street, London, W1B 2UW.

We are entitled to charge a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.
